<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2020 on std::bodun::blog</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/categories/2020/</link><description>Recent content in 2020 on std::bodun::blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/categories/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Program Loading and Memory Mapping in Linux</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/program-loading-and-memory-mapping-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/program-loading-and-memory-mapping-in-linux/</guid><description>The goal here is to familiarize yourself with how programs are loaded, dynamically paged, and some of the mechanics of signal handling and memory mapping in Linux</description></item><item><title>Scheduler Activation</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/scheduler-activation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/scheduler-activation/</guid><description>This is a summary on scheduler activation. To discuss about scheduler activation, we must first understand what is a thread. A thread of execution is the smallest sequence of programmed instructions that can be managed independently by a scheduler</description></item><item><title>Add MathJax v3 Support to Jekyll and Hugo</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/add-mathjax-v3-support-to-jekyll-and-hugo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/add-mathjax-v3-support-to-jekyll-and-hugo/</guid><description>I was using Mathjax v2 for a while and I heard v3 perform significantly better than v2. Many great tutorials explains explains how to add Mathjax support to Jekyll websites. Some of them only cover Mathjax v2. So here is the brief summary on how to add Mathjax v3 support to your Jekyll website (Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve migrated to Hugo but adding support to Hugo is also pretty similar)</description></item><item><title>Linux Program Measurement and mmap</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/linux-program-measurement-and-mmap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/linux-program-measurement-and-mmap/</guid><description>This is a summary over Linux kernel program measurement and mmap. The specs of our experiment environment is listed below. For more details regarding the CPU spec please refer to &lt;a
href="http://www.cpu-world.com/CPUs/Core_i7/Intel-Core%20i7%20i7-6800K.html"
target="_blank"
rel="noopener"
>
cpu world
&lt;/a> for more info</description></item><item><title>Memory Resource Management in VMware ESX Server</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/memory-resource-management-in-vmware-esx-server/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/memory-resource-management-in-vmware-esx-server/</guid><description>VMWare ESX Server is a software layer designed to multiplex hardware resources among virtual machines running unmodified commodity operating systems. ESX Server, different to VMware Workstation , is a type 1 hypervisor, which means it runs directly on bare metal. ESX Server focuses on running guest VMs without modifying the guest OSes at all, which is challenging.
Memory Virtualization is done by interposing an extra abstraction layer between a physical address from the VM&amp;rsquo;s point of view, and a machine address which represents the actual hardware memory.</description></item><item><title>Xen and the Art of Virtualization</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/xen-and-the-art-of-virtualization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/xen-and-the-art-of-virtualization/</guid><description>Xen is an x86 virtual machine monitor which allows multiple commodity operating systems to share conventional hardware in a safe and resource managed fashion, without sacrificing either performance or functionality. Xen is type I hypervisor, which directly runs on top of bare metal. We will summarize what Xen is what its attributes are.
paravirtualization - presents a virtual machine abstraction that is similar but not identical to the underlying hardware.</description></item><item><title>Start Linux Kernel Hacking</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/start-linux-kernel-hacking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/start-linux-kernel-hacking/</guid><description>This is a summary of how to compile and boot the Linux kernel on the KVM-qemu virtual machine. It covers how to get a VM running in KVM, how to build a customized kernel, and how to use GDB with the Linux kernel. The experiment is conducted on an amd64 architecture CPU. We use Ubuntu as our testing environment but the steps covered here should apply to other distros as well</description></item><item><title>Performance Anamoly of 802.11b</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/performance-anamoly-of-802.11b/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/performance-anamoly-of-802.11b/</guid><description>This research is conducted by Martin Heusse, Franck Rousseau, Cilles Berger-Sabbatel, Andrzej Duda on analyzing the performance of the IEEE 802.11b wireless local area networks. Degraded transmitting rate is caused by CSMA/CA channel access method</description></item><item><title>Exokernel</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/exokernel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/exokernel/</guid><description>Exokernel is a term every system researcher has heard of at some point in life. However, according to the &lt;a
href="https://pdos.csail.mit.edu/"
target="_blank"
rel="noopener"
>
PDOS
&lt;/a> group at MIT, there aren&amp;rsquo;t any exokernel-based operating systems in active use today. It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to discover what ideas exokernels brought to the OS high-level design and some potential drawbacks of such design choice</description></item><item><title>Sketch on the UNIX Timesharing System</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/sketch-on-the-unix-timesharing-system/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/sketch-on-the-unix-timesharing-system/</guid><description>Unix is general-purpose, multi-user, interactive operating system, it offers several new features hardly found in other larger operating systems back in the day. These features include (1) a hierarchical file system incorporating demountable volumes; (2) compatible file, device, and inter-process I/O; (3) the ability to initiate asynchronous processes; (4) system command language selectable on a per-user basis; and (5) over 100 subsystems including a dozen languages</description></item><item><title>Monads in Haskell</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/monads-in-haskell/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/monads-in-haskell/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve scratched my head for quite a while trying to understand the concept of monad in Haskell. This is a brief summary of monads. I take William Cook&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a
href="http://www.cs.utexas.edu/~wcook/anatomy/anatomy.htm"
target="_blank"
rel="noopener"
>
Anatomy of Programming Languages
&lt;/a> as my reference</description></item><item><title>Singular Value Decomposition</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/singular-value-decomposition/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/singular-value-decomposition/</guid><description>Unitary matrices and the Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) are two important concepts in linear algebra. In order to fully understand these concepts, we will need to first discuss orthogonality. Most materials are converted in Advanced Linear Algebra: Foundations to Frontiers taught by professor &lt;a
href="https://www.cs.utexas.edu/~rvdg/"
target="_blank"
rel="noopener"
>
Robert van de Geijn
&lt;/a>. This is a brief summary over the important concepts covered in Chapter 2</description></item></channel></rss>