<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>writing on std::bodun::blog</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in writing on std::bodun::blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Starting Out PhD</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/starting-out-phd/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/starting-out-phd/</guid><description>Today marks the third month of my PhD life. Things finally start to become a little bit clearer. I finally have some potentially concrete ideas to work on.
Finding a research topic was the most difficult part. For several months, I was wondering around like a headless chicken, reading papers after papers: serverless, ML inference, compiler, pathlet routing, RDMA, you name it. The feeling of not having a topic was suffocating.</description></item><item><title>Writing in the Sciences - Writing Process</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/writing-in-the-sciences-writing-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/writing-in-the-sciences-writing-process/</guid><description>This post covers the topics mentioned in Writing in the Sciences offered on Coursera.
Writing Process The writing process includes three steps:
Prewriting Collect and organize information Brainstorm take-home messages Work out ideas away from the computer Develop a road map Writing the first draft Putting ideas together in organized prose Revision Read out loud Cut the clutter Verb check Get feedback A lot of people often convolute step 2 and 3.</description></item><item><title>Writing in the Sciences - Structure</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/writing-in-the-sciences-structure/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/writing-in-the-sciences-structure/</guid><description>This post covers how to improve sentence structures, and builds to to writing strong paragraphs. Most contents comes from the &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/sciwrite">Writing in the Sciences&lt;/a> course offered on &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/">Coursera&lt;/a></description></item><item><title>Writing in the Sciences - Verbs</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/writing-in-the-sciences-verbs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/writing-in-the-sciences-verbs/</guid><description>This is an overview of the second chapter of &lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/learn/sciwrite">Writing in the Sciences&lt;/a> offered by &lt;a href="https://www.stanford.edu/">Stanford&lt;/a>. This chapter focuses on writing with strong, active verbs. Lessons include how to</description></item><item><title>Writing in the Sciences - Cut the Clutter</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/writing-in-the-sciences-cut-the-clutter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/writing-in-the-sciences-cut-the-clutter/</guid><description>This is an overview over the first chapter of Writing in the Sciences offered by Stanford.
The secret of good writing is to strip every sentence to its cleanest components. Every word that serves no function, every long word that could be a short word, every adverb that carries the same meaning that&amp;rsquo;s already in the verb, every passive construction that leaves the reader unsure of who is doing what. These are the thousand and one adulterants that weaken the strength of a sentence.</description></item></channel></rss>