<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on std::bodun:blog</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on std::bodun:blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Congruence Closure</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/congruence_closure/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/congruence_closure/</guid><description>This is a summary of how to compute congruence closure. I implemented the algorithm to compute congruence closure and thought I&amp;rsquo;d never forget it.</description></item><item><title>Program Loading and Memory Mapping in Linux</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/programloadingandmemorymappinginlinux/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/programloadingandmemorymappinginlinux/</guid><description>The goal here is to familiarize yourself with how programs are loaded, dynamically paged, and some of the mechanics of signal handling and memory mapping in Linux.</description></item><item><title>Scheduler Activation</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/scheduleractivation/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/scheduleractivation/</guid><description>What is a thread? A thread of execution is the smallest sequence of programmed instructions that can be managed independently by a scheduler.</description></item><item><title>Add MathJax v3 Support to Jekyll</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/mathjaxjekyll/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/mathjaxjekyll/</guid><description>I was using Mathjax v2 for a while and I heard v3 perform significantly better than v2. Many great tutorials explains explains how to add Mathjax support to Jekyll websites.</description></item><item><title>Linux Program Measurement and mmap</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/linuxkernelmeasurementandmmap/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/linuxkernelmeasurementandmmap/</guid><description>This is a summary over Linux kernel program measurement and mmap. The specs of our experiment environment is listed below. For more details regarding the CPU spec please refer to cpu world.</description></item><item><title>Memory Resource Management in VMware ESX Server</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/vmwareesxserver/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/vmwareesxserver/</guid><description>VMWare ESX Server is a software layer designed to multiplex hardware resources among virtual machines running unmodified commodity operating systems. ESX Server, different to VMware Workstation, is a type 1 hypervisor, which means it runs directly on bare metal.</description></item><item><title>Xen and the Art of Virtualization</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/xenvirtualization/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/xenvirtualization/</guid><description>Xen is an x86 virtual machine monitor which allows multiple commodity operating systems to share conventional hardware in a safe and resource managed fashion, without sacrificing either performance or functionality.</description></item><item><title>Start Linux Kernel Hacking</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/kernelhacking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/kernelhacking/</guid><description>This is a summary of how to compile and boot the Linux kernel on the KVM-qemu virtual machine. It covers how to get a VM running in KVM, how to build a customized kernel, and how to use GDB with the Linux kernel.</description></item><item><title>Performance Anamoly of 802.11b</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/wireless_anomaly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/wireless_anomaly/</guid><description>This research is conducted by Martin Heusse, Franck Rousseau, Cilles Berger-Sabbatel, Andrzej Duda on analyzing the performance of the IEEE 802.</description></item><item><title>Exokernel</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/exokernel/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/exokernel/</guid><description>Exokernel is a term every system researcher has heard of at some point in life. However, according to the PDOS group at MIT, there aren&amp;rsquo;t any exokernel-based operating systems in active use today.</description></item><item><title>Sketch on the UNIX Timesharing System</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/unix/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/unix/</guid><description>Unix is general-purpose, multi-user, interactive operating system, it offers several new features hardly found in other largers operating systems back in the day.</description></item><item><title>Monads in Haskell</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/monad/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/monad/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve scratched my head for quite a while trying to understand the concept of monad in Haskell. This is a brief summary of monads.</description></item><item><title>Singular Value Decomposition</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/svd/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/svd/</guid><description>Unitary matrices and the Singular Value Decomposition (SVD) are two important concepts in linear algebra. In order to fully understand these concepts, we will need to first discuss orthogonality.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Probabilistic Clock Synchronization</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/probabilistic_clock_synchronization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/probabilistic_clock_synchronization/</guid><description>This post is meant to discuss the probabilistic clock synchronization technique. The main goal of this technique is to bound the difference between systems by setting up an upper bound.</description></item><item><title>How to Put Papers on ArXiv</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/arxivsubmition/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/arxivsubmition/</guid><description>I was recently trying to put my research paper draft on ArXiv. I thought it would be as simple as submitting the pdf file, which should take approximately less than ten minutes.</description></item><item><title>A Little Review on Barrelfish Memory Management</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/operatingsystemmemorymanagement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/operatingsystemmemorymanagement/</guid><description>The memory management has been mentioned numerous times and still remains huge topic. virtual vs. physical memory, physical frame allocation, MMUs, page faults, address space layout, and demand paging and swapping are familiar terms for every undergrad in college.</description></item><item><title>Pascal GPU memory and cache hierarchy</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/gpumemoryhierarchy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/gpumemoryhierarchy/</guid><description>Memory access efﬁciency is an important factor in fully utilizing the computational power of graphics processing units (GPUs). However, many GPU vendors like NVIDIA kept the GPU memory hierarchy as a secret.</description></item><item><title>Map Reduce</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/mapreduce/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/mapreduce/</guid><description>I was always interested by the name &amp;ldquo;map reduce&amp;rdquo; since two years ago when I first heard this term. But I&amp;rsquo;ve never put any effor to know the concept until Chris mentioned it in class because it will be on the next exam so I figured I&amp;rsquo;d better figure out what is going on before it was too late.</description></item><item><title>Networks</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/networks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/networks/</guid><description>The concept of a worldwide of networks of information was introduced long before the technology used to build the internet. The first workable prototype came in the late 1960s with the creation of ARPANET(The Advanced Research Projects Agency Network).</description></item><item><title>File System Design</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/filesystem/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/filesystem/</guid><description>What exactly is a file system? The general concept is that the file system provides naming organization. It manages the physical disk layout such as picking a block constituting a file, balancing locality with expandability, and managing free space.</description></item><item><title>Disk Introduction</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/disks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/disks/</guid><description>This chapter is all about disk. Before we start. We won&amp;rsquo;t go deep into the mechanical part of disk operation; rather we will be focusing on general concept related to disk and algorithms to improve disk performance.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Memory Mechanisms</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/virtualaddressmechanism/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/virtualaddressmechanism/</guid><description>As we can see in the previous post, all allocation algorithms we discussed lead to external fragmentation. As time goes by, external fragmentation is going to get worse and we need solutions for the problem.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Memory Overview</title><link>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/virtualaddress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.bodunhu.com/blog/posts/virtualaddress/</guid><description>I love pointers. Pointer is very a useful feature in programming languages like C/C++. I can pass weird hexidecimal numbers to a function and then it will magically locate where the program is in memory.</description></item></channel></rss>